（ギャモン）ああっ。　え～い。
え～い。
Your sister?
（ダウト）
妹？　あぁ　あれのことか…。→
Ah, you mean that?
別に　どうなろうと
知ったことではない。
I couldn't care less about what happened to her.
なにっ？！　ケッ。
What?!
Although if it helps us achieve our goal,
（ダウト）むしろ　我々の大いなる
目的のために　役に立てたのなら→
あの　つまらぬ命にも→
then I must admit even her dull life has a meaning.
少しは　生まれた意味が
あったというものだ。
ミハルまで　巻き込みやがって。
あいつら　許せねえ！
They tried to drag Miharu into this!
I won't let them get away with this!
（女性キャスター）「謎の覆面パズル作家！
地堂　刹！　大スランプ？！→
The mysterious puzzle maker, Chido Setsu, is in a slump?!
今をときめく　流行パズル作家
地堂　刹に異変です！→
Something must be wrong with the famous puzzle master of our days, Chido Setsu!
不動の地位を誇っていた
人気投票でも→
He was unmovable from his top position, but now he's quickly falling in the popularity rankings!
一気に　順位を落とす事態に
なっているんです！」。
（エレナ）全く…。
何やってんのよ　ガリレオは！
Just what is Galileo thinking?
lost te saguri de sagashiteta
Lost, trying to find it blindly with my hands.
tozasareta mirai no kotae nante doko ni mo nai
But the key to the locked future is nowhere to be found.
hashiru shoudou ima kaidoku funou
Undecipherable urges surging.
found kudaketa hazu no unmei wo
I found the fate I believed broken.
mijukuna yume no naka de kikoetekitan da
I heard it in my immature dream.
saigo made I'll be there for you
I'll be there for you till the very end.
tachitomaranai kono hari dake wa
I can't stop. I hear nothing else.
boku no asu wo kizamu oto tsukisasu
How this needle carves my future.
shinjitsu kara nigetara ima
I'm running away from the truth now.
genjitsu ni mo maketara ima
I'm losing to reality now.
nani ga nokoru no (nokoru no)
What will be left?
kazoekirenai kono kizu dake ga
The countless scars on my body
boku no kinou wo zanzou toshite kataru
are the only thing telling the story of my past.
unmei ga hodokete mo ima
Even if fate falls apart now,
sonzai wo kowashite mo ima
even if existence shatters now,
boku no michi wo yuku yo
I'm walkng down my own path.
It's now or never.
This is what they say: "Live your life today."
There will always be, there will always be a way.
The Lost Sheep, Galileo
I investigated the dome after what happened, but I couldn't find anything.
（キュービック）
調べてみたけど　前回のドームからは
何も見つからなかったよ。
彼らは消えてしまった…。
They just vanished.
まるで　最初から
存在しなかったみたいにね。
It's like they were never even there.
（ノノハ）今回も　オルペウス・オーダーに関する
手がかりは　何も無し…　か。
So we still don't have any clues on them.
（アナ）アナが思うに　あの人たち　カイトの
お知り合いさんみたいだったけど。
I think... those people seemed to know Kaito.
Have you met them before?
カイト　会ったことあるの？
（カイト）いや　分からねぇ。
一体　何者なんだ？　あいつら。
No, I don't remember anything like that.
Just who the hell are they?
何が目的で　俺たちの中…。
What are they trying to achieve by-
（ギャモン）んな事は　どうだっていい！
（２人）あっ。
Who fucking cares?!
やつらが手段を選ばねえんなら
こっちだって黙っちゃいられねえ。
If they're gonna play rough, I can't just watch quietly!
俺は　やつらをぶっ潰す！
ただ　それだけだ。
I'll crush them like bugs. That's all.
ギャモン君…。
Gammon...
（武田）ハー　ハッハッハッハッハッ！
大門君　これを見たまえ！
Look at this, Daimon!
Naoki found a mistake in that genius Chido Setsu's puzzle!
（相沢）ナオッキーさんが　あの天才
地堂　刹のパズルの出題ミスを→
発見したんだぞ！
えっ？！
あんたたち…　少しは
場の空気を読みなさいよ！
You two just can't take a hint, can you?
何　言ってんだ。　そんなもん
印刷ミスに決まってんだろ！
Oh, come on, it's obviously just a printing mistake.
こりゃ　ひでぇ。　これが　本当に
地堂　刹のパズルかよ？！
Holy crap! Is this really a Chido Setsu puzzle?
正真正銘の出来損ないじゃねえか。
あっ。
This is obviously a huge blunder!
こんなパズル…
作るやつじゃなかったのになぁ。
His puzzles weren't like this before.
がっ。
え～と　誰？　地堂　刹って？
Um... Who's this Chido Setsu guy?
謎の覆面パズル作家だよ。
A mysterious masked puzzle maker.
大人気だったけど　最近は
目も当てられねえって噂→
He was really popular, but he's said to be in ruins recently.
本当だったんだな。
わっ！　ネットでの評判もさんざんだ。
I guess it's true.
His ratings on the net are terrible too.
「地堂　刹　引退までの日数を
予想するスレッド」だって。
There's this thread where they're guessing how many days it'll take until he retires!
（武田）地堂刹の時代も終わりだな。
まっ　僕には　すでに見えていたが。
Chido Setsu's sun has set. I have foreseen this.
（相沢）さすがは　ナオ　ナオ　ナオッキー。
You're amazing, Nao-Nao-Naoki!
こいつのパズルの良さは→
His puzzles were great because they were filled with a pure love of puzzles.
パズルへの純粋な思いが　満ちあふれ
てるところだったんだよ。
けど　今の地堂　刹から
感じられるのは→
But now all I can feel is deep anger and hatred... and nothing else.
底知れぬ怒り…　憎しみ…
ただ　それだけだ。
（フリーセル）ゲームは　本格的に
新たなるフェーズへと移行した。
The game has moved on an essentially different phase.
そう考えていいのかい？　ホイスト。
Is that right, Whist?
（ホイスト）そのとおりでございます。
Very much so.
皆様方には　引き続き
大門カイト様たちとのゲームを→
I shall continue to follow in your footsteps and directly challenge Daimon Kaito and his friends.
直接　楽しんでいただきますので
そのおつもりで。
I hope that is well with you.
（ピノクル）ふっ…　引き続きねぇ…。
There ain't no "continue."
何か　ご不満でしょうか？
俺らの本命は　大門カイトでしょう？
Is something the matter?
Our target is Daimon Kaito, isn't he?
どうして　雑魚キャラまで
相手にしなくちゃなんないわけ？
Why do we have to bother with all those annoying small fries?
（メランコリィ）レプリカ・リングの開発が
順調だからって→
Just because the replica rings' development is going well
ちょっと　お遊びが
過ぎるんじゃなくて？
doesn't mean we should just play around carelessly.
（フリーセル）ねえ　ホイスト。
Say, Whist.
君は　何も知らないのかい？
You don't know anything?
はい。
Indeed.
まあ　いいや。
ご協力　感謝いたします。
Well, whatever.
Thank you for your cooperation.
（ピノクル）ああ。　そういや
今日は　ダウト　居ないね？
By the way, where's Doubt today?
時間にうるさいあいつが
遅刻なんて珍しい。
He's always so anal about punctuality, and now he's late?
（ホイスト）ダウト様からは　欠席の
ご連絡をいただいております。
Sir Doubt has contacted me in regards to his absence today.
Huh?
Looks like he's found himself...
（ミゼルカ）どうやら　彼
見つけちゃったみたいね。
新しいおもちゃをね。
a new toy.
ただいま。
I'm back.
Welcome home, Gammon!
（ミハル）あっ　お兄ちゃん
お帰りなさい。
おう　ミハル。　お客さんか？
Hey, Miharu. Do we have a guest?
うん。　今ね　お兄ちゃんのお友達が
来てるんだよ。
Yeah. A friend of yours came by.
Huh?
ケッ　てめえ！
ここで　何しやがる？！
You bastard! What are you doing here?!
お兄ちゃん！
ケッ。
Gammon!
（ダウト）場所を変えようか？
Shall we take this outside?
てめえ　一体　どういうつもりだ？
What the hell are you scheming?
勘違いするな。
別に　お前の妹に興味はない。
Don't misunderstand me. I'm not interested in your sister.
あれの利用価値は
もう　ないからな。
She's of no use to me anymore.
Now, let's get down to business.
本題に入ろう。
今日は　お前に用があって　来た。
I'm here for you today.
Sakanoue Gammon! Join us and lead humankind to a new future!
逆之上ギャモン。　我々と共に
人類を　新たなる未来へ導け。
どうやら私は　お前を
過小評価していたようだ。
It would seem that I have underestimated your value.
前回のゲームで分かった。
But in the last game I understood
お前には　我々の理想のために
働くだけの素質がある。
that you have the qualities to work toward our ideals.
人間は　かつて　神々によって
その才能を疎まれ→
The gods became jealous of the human intellect
聡明な頭脳に鍵をかけられた。
and locked away the true potential of our genius.
全能の力を取り戻し
楽園へと回帰するためには→
To release our full power and return to paradise,
その鍵を解くしかない。
we must first release that lock.
レプリカ・リングの力によってな。
With the power of the replica rings.
だから　俺の妹や…
アイリや…　副会長に…。
And that's why you gave them
to my sister, Airi, and the vice president?
必要な犠牲だ。
They were necessary sacrifices.
彼女たちから得られた
データによって→
We used the data gathered from them to bring forth the power of the replica rings.
レプリカ・リングは　順調に
力をなしている。
レプリカが完成しさえすれば
正統なるリングに選ばれなかった→
Once we complete the replica, even the masses of commoners
有象無象の者たちも　次の段階へと
進化することができるだろう。
who were not chosen by the true ring
can advance to the next stage of evolution.
そして　共に人類を
導こうではないか。
Join us, and we will lead humankind together!
逆之上ギャモン。　オルペウス・オーダーに来い！
Sakanoue Gammon,
come to the Orpheus Order!
てめえら…　どうかしてやがるぜ！
You guys are nuts!
色よい返事を期待している。
I'm expecting a favorable answer.
けえ～っ。
オルペウス・オーダー！
Damn Orpheus Order!
（メイズ）もしもし。　あっ　はい。
Hello? Ah, yes!
東京パズルランド建設の件ですか？
Is it about the Tokyo Puzzle Land constructions?
ただいま　担当の者と
替わりますので。
Just a moment, I'll put you through to the person in charge.
（メイズ）まちづくり課長！
Head of Construction and Development!
（ダイスマン）
よ～っ！　ギャモンちゃんじゃない！
元気にしてた？
Oh my god, is that Gammon?!
How ya been, bro?
おい　ずいぶん変わっちまったな。
This place sure has changed.
（フンガ）新生ＰＯＧは　皆様に
愛される存在でなければならない。
The reborn POG must be a well-loved organization.
それが
新しい総責任者の方針でな。
That is the guideline our new leader has put in place.
Anyway, what brings you here, Gammon?
（ダイスマン）それで　ギャモンちゃん。
今日は　何の用？
ちっとばかし　お前らの力を
借りたい用事があってな。
There's a bit of business I need your help with.
わけありみたいじゃない。
なになに～？
You look serious.
What's up?
聞かせてもらおうか。
ああ。
Please do tell us.
Well...
（エレナ）大変みたいね。　地堂センセ。
アントワネット…。
You look troubled, Master Chido.
Antoinette.
これで　あんたにも
分かったでしょ。
Do you see how harsh the puzzle business is now?
パズル業界の厳しさってもんが。
But don't worry, your slump will end-
まっ　スランプくらい
時間がたてば　なんとか…。
…んなことは　どうでもいい！
パズルなんて　どうだっていいんだ。
Who cares about that?!
I don't give a rat's ass about puzzles!
俺には　やらなきゃならねえことが
あるんだよ。
There's something I have to do.
ちょっと乗りなさいよ。
Get in the car.
そう…　そんなことが…。
Th-That's terrible...
今ＰＯＧのやつらに　オルペウス・オーダーの
居場所を探ってもらってる。
I asked the POG people to help me find where the Orpheus Order are hiding.
どうするつもり？
あいつらの居場所を突き止めて→
And then what?
I'll pinpoint their location and raid their hideout.
殴り込む。
この手で　あいつをぶん殴らねえと
収まらねえんだよ！
I won't rest till I beat the shit out of them with my bare hands!
I can't contain my anger!
俺の腹の虫がな！
ちょっと　何　それ？！
What are you saying?
そんなことで　やつらに勝ったって
言えるわけ？
Would you really be able to say you won then?
パズルで売られたけんかは
パズルで返すのが→
They challenged you in a puzzle fight, so isn't it your style to return it with puzzles?
あんたの流儀じゃなかったの？
けんか？　バカ言ってんじゃねえ。
A fight? Don't kid with me now.
これはもう　戦争なんだよ！
パズルなんざ　知ったことか。
This is war! Puzzles have nothing to do with it!
それ　本気で言ってるの？
Are you serious?
あんたが　パズルをやめたら
悲しむ人だって居るのよ。
If you quit making puzzles, it'll make people sad.
はっ。　居るわけは　ねえだろ
そんなやつ。
As if there's anyone like that...
元はと言えば　金のために
作ってたパズルだ。
I was doing it for the money to begin with.
未練なんざ
これっぽっちも　ねえよ。
I'm not attached to them at all.
あいつ　マジで　やばいわね。
This is really, really bad.
もしもし。　あたしよ。　姫川エレナ。
Hello. It's me, Himekawa Elena.
頼みたいことがあるの…
あんたに。
There's something I'd like to ask you.
ねえ　これ　一体どういう状況？
What's going on here?
さあ　登校したら
こうなってたんだ。
Dunno, it was like this when I got here.
見損なったぜ…　ギャモン。
あぁ？！
I'm disappointed in you, Gammon.
まさか　お前が
そんなやつだったとはな。
I didn't think you would do it.
てめえ　何言ってんだ？
とぼけんな！
What are you even talking about?
Don't play dumb!
あれは…　お前の仕業だろうが！
You did that, didn't you?
（一同）あぁ。
何　あれ？　「カイトへ。　カカカバー　カバーバー」。
What's that?
To Kaito,
Ron-ron-ron-mo ron-mo-mo...
モールス信号だ！
It's Morse code!
"If you're mad, make a better puzzle than me!"
「悔しかったら　俺様よりも
うまいパズルを作ってみやがれ！」。
そう書いてあるんだよ！
That's what it says!
I've never seen that! It wasn't me!
知らねえよ　あんなもん！
俺じゃねえ！
知らばっくれんな！　あそこに
ちゃんと　名前があるじゃねえか！
Don't play the innocent! Your name's written there clean and clear!
なっ？！
本当だ。　普通に書いてある。
He's right, it's there.
俺が書くわきゃねえだろう。
Why would I write my name there?!
ハッ　そういうバカなところが
いかにも　お前らしいぜ！
おい！
That stupidity is just like you!
Hey!
お前が　俺をなめてるのは
よ～く分かった。
I get it now. You're looking down on me.
俺はソルヴァー専門で　パズルなんか
作れねえって思ってやがんだろ？！
You think I can't make puzzles because I'm a Solver specialist?
はぁ？！
いい機会だ。
This is a good chance. I accept your challenge!
この挑戦　買ったぜ！
今日は　俺が　ギヴァーだ。
俺の作ったパズルを解いてみやがれ！
Today, I'm the Giver! Just try solving my puzzle!
うっ！　くっ　なにっ…。
What the...
いいか　各階に
合計３つのパズルを用意した。
I've prepared three puzzles, one on each floor!
それを全部解いて
俺のいる屋上まで来い！
Solve them all, then come to me on the roof!
If you can make it on time, you win.
「制限時間内にたどりつけたら
お前の勝ちだ」。
って　俺が　カイトにやったシチュエーションと
同じじゃねえか～！　くっそ～！
Hey, this is the exact same thing I did!
Dammit!
まあ　似た者同士って
ことじゃないの？
Well, you two are so similar.
あぁ？！　アントワネット！
Antoinette!
なんで　てめえが　ここに！
つうか　何なんだ　この流れは！
Why are you here? And what the hell's going on here?
こうなったからには　あんたも
やるしかないんじゃない？
You don't have any choice but to do it now, do you?
なに～？
それとも　あの天才→
What?
Or... are you afraid that the genius Chido Setsu would lose to an amateur?
地堂　刹先生が　素人ギヴァーごときに
負けるのが怖いのかしら？
んなわけは　ねえだろ！
あいつの　だっせえパズルなんか→
Yeah, right!
I'll smash all his lame little puzzles!
俺様が　この手で
ぶっ潰してやんよ　やんよ！
I don't really get it, but do your best, Gammon!
まあ　よく分かんないけど
ギャモン君　ガンバ！
ファイト！　やんや　やんや～！
Do it! Go-go-go-go!
ヘヘヘヘッ　パズルタイムの　始まりだ～！
It's puzzle time, goddammit!
あぁ？！　「６つのピースを使って
Ｈの字を作れ！」だぁ？
Huh? "Make a letter H out of the pieces"?
Kiss my ass!
ふざけやがって！
俺が前に作ったＴの字を
Ｈにしただけだろうが！
He just turned the "T" I made into an "H"!
ちぇっ　くだらねえ！
Pathetic.
I don't have time to play with puzzles!
俺は　パズルなんざに
かまっている暇は　ねえんだよ！
できた！
Done!
はっ！　また　俺のパズルのパクリかよ！
He stole my puzzle again!
こんなもん　一瞬で…。
This only takes a flash!
こりゃあ…。
This...
さすがは　素人ギヴァー。
心の声
He's really an amateur.
びっくりするほど直球で
稚拙なパズルだぜ…。
These puzzles are all frank and childish.
心の声
だが…　ただのパクリなんかじゃねえ。
But...
He didn't just steal my puzzles.
心の声
俺のパズルを踏まえたうえで
あいつなりの工夫を→
He based them off mine,
but he also forced his own style on them!
ガンガン凝らしてやがる…。
心の声
やるじゃねえか。
Not half-bad.
何やってんだ…　俺。
心の声
What am I doing?
パズルなんざ　どうだっていいって
思ってたはずなのによ…。
I thought I didn't care about puzzles.
何なんだ？　パズルって。
心の声
What are puzzles?
俺にとって　こいつは！
心の声
What do they mean to me?
また　行き止まりかよ！
Another dead end?
あぁ～　やめた　やめた！
Just give up already.
どうせ　設計でも　ミスったんだろ。
このパズルには　答えなんか　ねえ。
It must be a construction mistake.
This puzzle has no solution.
いや　そんなはずは…。
No, that can't be...
大体　これが解けたからって→
We're not getting anything out of solving it either!
一銭の稼ぎにも
なんねえじゃねえか。
俺は降りるぜ。
I'm going home.
好きにしろよ。
あぁ？！
Feel free to.
俺は　やる。　こんな　おもしれえパズル
金なんかには換えられねえぜ。
I'm gonna finish it.
This puzzle is so fun it's worth more than anything money could buy.
ざけんな。
As if!
このパズルを解くのは
てめえじゃねえ！　この俺だ！
You ain't solving this puzzle!
Because I am!
そうか。　俺は…。
心の声
I see... That's it...
よし…　解けた。
Solved it.
いいパズルだぜ。
This was a good puzzle.
おっと　いけねぇ！
I gotta hurry!
残念だったなぁ　ギャモン。
１０秒の遅刻だ。
Too bad, Gammon.
You're ten seconds late.
時間には　間に合わなかったぜ。
いいや　間に合った。
You didn't make it on time.
No, I did.
あぁ？！
間に合ったんだ。
I definitely did.
俺は　もう少しで
掛けがえのねえもんを→
Just a little longer, and I would've thrown something irreplaceable down the drain.
ドブに捨てちまうところだったぜ。
ギャモン…。
Gammon...
カイト…　俺は…。
Kaito, I...
うわっ！
よっしゃ～！　かかった！
Yes! Got him!
あの時の恨み　俺は
忘れてたわけじゃねえからな！
Don't think I forgave you for that!
You're still pissed off about that?!
てめえ　まだ　そんなことを！
あたりめえだ　こらっ！
ガキか？！
Of course I am!
Are you a kid?
はぁ～　ガキっていうやつが
ガキなんだよ。
Look who's talking!
全く　世話を焼かせるんだから。
You're such a pain in the butt.
えっ。　俺だい。　分かったのか？！
It's me. Have you found it?
どこなんだ？
オルペウス・オーダーのアジトは？！
Where is the Orpheus Order hiding?
誰ちゃん？
（男）「速達ちゃん」。
Who're you, sweet-cheeks?
Your sweet express delivery.
（男）こちらに　サインをお願いします。
Please sign here.
（ピノクル）ダウトあてだよ。
（ダウト）バカな。
It's for you, Doubt.
Impossible. How could I get mail here?
ここに　郵便など届くわけが…。
差出人は　逆之上ギャモン。
The sender is Sakanoue Gammon.
（ダウト）やつが　なぜ
我々の居場所を？！
He found our hideout.
（フリーセル）うっふ。
（ダイスマン）ふっふ。
（ダウト）これは…　パズル！
This is a puzzle!
（ダウト）「ｒｅｆｕｓａｌ」。　拒否。
"Refusal." He's refusing.
断るというのか？　私の誘いを！
He's refusing my invitation?
それじゃあ
５０点の解答だよ。
That's just half of the answer.
隣のマスを
下から読んでごらん。
Look at the next column from bottom up.
フッ…　「ｆｏｏｌｉｓｈ」。
"Foolish!"
バカだってさ。
（メランコリィ）アハハハハハッ。
He's calling you a fool.
（フリーセル）どうやら　今回は　まんまと
彼にしてやられたみたいだね。
Looks like he cleverly outsmarted you this time.
（ギャモン）へい。
どうしたの？　お兄ちゃん。
What's wrong, Gammon?
いや　何でもねぇ。
それより　ミハル　見てろよ。
Nothing's wrong.
But take a look at this, Miharu!
これからは　もっと
おもしれえパズルを作ってやる。
I'll start making more interesting puzzles from now.
パズルバカを　うならせるような
すっげえやつをな！
All the puzzle maniacs will love them!
うん。　お兄ちゃん！
That's great, Brother!
ＰＯＧまで動き出すとは…
ますます面白くなってきたね。
To think that even the POG would make a move...
This is getting interesting.
（ホイスト）フリーセル様。
分かっているよ。
Sir Freecell.
I know.
新しいゲームの準備が
できたんだろう？
Are the preparations for the new game finished?
はい。
Yes.
行こう。
Let's go...
√学園へ。
to Root Academy.
eiyuu kidori itsu datte shinjita muteki no kankaku
I think I'm a hero and believe that I'm invincible.
tatakatte iru no wa chikyuu no tame nanka janai
I'm not fighting for the world.
motto mai peesu de
It's for a more personal,
sou motto shoujikina negai no tame
a more honest wish.
nando to naku kizutsuite mo
No matter how many times I'm hurt